

73 Marshall St., Waterloo, ON, N2J 2T5

🛮 (+1) 647-238-9818 | 💌 pranavp2810@gmail.com | 🧥 pranavp.dev | 🖸 shadowp2810 | 🛅 vanpp

# **Summary**

Working towards mastering JavaScript web and mobile full stack and Python stack. Can check out my github. I'm interested in opportunities to further your business and build my reputation. Currently located in Canada and have a Canadian Open Work Permit (PGWP). B.Sc. Computer Science graduate, AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate, and CompTIA Security+ certified. Dedicated to expanding my technical expertise and ability. Passion for Software, and its applications to Design, Finance and Health. Currently open to all opportunities and actively pursuing a role in software development, technology and business analysis, UX Design and Research, or people centric roles.

## **Certifications**

AWS Solutions Architect Associate (2021-2024); CompTIA Security+ (2021-2024);

## Skills\_

JavaScript. Python. Pandas. React-Native. React. NodeJS. MERN Stack. Figma. UI Design. UX Research. AWS Services (EC2. Lambda. S3. AWS Amplify. API Gateway. ECS. SNS. SQS. VPC. Route53. CloudFront. IAM. AutoScaling. DynamoDB. CloudFormation. Cloud-Watch. AWS WAF. GuardDuty. Shield. RDS.) Docker. GraphQL. TypeScript. MongoDB. SQL. Kali-Linux. Java. HTML5 / CSS. Sketch. Network security. Risk management. Threat intelligence. Data and host security. Identity management. Cryptography and PKI. Excel.

# Projects and Professional Development \_\_\_\_\_

PERSONAL PROJECTS 2021 - Now

- · Developed using Python Pandas, Algorithmic Technical Indicators for Cryptos, and a Backtesting engine to test strategies. With it developed a successful trading algorithm for Cryptos that has also been backtested on open source Freqtrade bot.
- · Built a local market place mobile application using React Native Expo with best practices based on CodeWithMosh course.
- Built a video rental management application with best practices, Font End using React and Back End using Express NodeJS and MongoDB.
- Built a responsive landing page for a cloud hosting provider with HTML5/CSS3 based on CodeWithMosh course.
- Built a React Native Typescript Twitter Clone and WhatsApp Clone using front-end React Native Expo App for Android and iOS and back-end AWS Amplify, Cognito Auth, S3 Storage, DynamoDB, and GraphQL API based on NotJustDev tutorials. Added to it comments screen with full functionality and custom authentication screen.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT 2021 - Now

- Udemy: Master Digital Product Design UX Research UI Design by Rob Sutcliffe.
- Udemy: The Complete Financial Analyst and Excel Course by 365 Careers.
- CodeWithMosh: HTML/CSS3, JavaScript, React, NodeJS, React Native

UNIVERSITY PROJECTS 2015 - 2020

- Developed a traffic simulator program in Java. Maple to visualize the data to show that even in a no bottleneck scenario, traffic jams can occur.
- Implementation of Search Algorithms and Reinforcement learning using JavaScript.
- Designed a new UI and UX for university's mobile app addressing previous shortcomings.
- Worked on team project of single-player 2D platform web game requiring asset creation, game engine and level editor.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

#### **P28INKS Apparel Store**

Waterloo, ON, Canada

CREATOR

Oct. 2020 - Dec. 2020

- Set up and management of online Shopify store, and print on demand service for automated order and shipping.
- Design of all apparel and Search Engine Optimization (SEO).

### **Memorial University of Newfoundland**

St. John's, NL, Canada

COMPUTER SCIENCE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Jan. 2018 - May. 2018

Researched and reported on Blockchain, Distributed Systems, IOT, and Cloud Technology.

#### **Memorial University of Newfoundland**

St. John's, NL, Canada

SOCIOLINGUISTIC RESEARCH ASSISTANT

April. 2016 - Aug. 2016

• Detailed transcription of interviews with focus on phonetic shifting.

# Education \_\_\_\_

#### MUN(Memorial University of Newfoundland)

St. John's, NL, Canada

**B.Sc. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE** 

Sep. 2015 - Feb. 2020